<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Londons lamentation for the loss of their charter</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A49100</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13659132</idno>
  <idno type="VID">101056</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240892615</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2936</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R971</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">13659132</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A49100)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 101056)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 793:35)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Londons lamentation for the loss of their charter</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for A. Banks,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1683.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">London (England). --  Charter.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:101056:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Londons Lamentation</hi> For the Loss of their CHARTER.</head>
            <p>AH wo to us! wo to us! we have lost our Charter, our Franchises, our Liberties, which were Royal Priviledges in the hands of Subjects, given to us by the Kings and Queens of <hi>England,</hi> by several gracious Grants, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which were to us of great Benefit, Power and Freedom, which we through Princely Bounty enjoyed above others: We indeed derived our Corporation from the Kings of <hi>England,</hi> yea, from thence proceeded its Origination and Essence; but we have now lost those Priviledges and Franchises which we did enjoy; so that we (by sad experience) find that <hi>Corporations</hi> are not immortal, though this of <hi>London</hi> hath been very long-liv'd, very great and splendid; yet we find that Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties and Franchises may belost, and forfeited (as the great <hi>Bracton</hi> saith) either through the Abuse, or for want of the right use there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and that so large is the extent of Royal Prerogative, that so migh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty is the Power of the Prince, that he can call in question the <hi>Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chises</hi> of the most Magnificent <hi>Corporations,</hi> and if those <hi>Franchises</hi> (even those Royal Priviledges (through the Princes Bouney, put in the hand of a Subject) be misused, they may be seized into the Kings hands, and He that granted them to us, through our Misuse thereof) can take them away from us. Great were our Priviledges, and sumptuous was the Administration of the Government of our City (though through our Abuse of our <hi>Franchises,</hi> our Glory is now eclipsed; for our <hi>Common Council</hi> was as the <hi>Parliament</hi> of our <hi>City,</hi> and our <hi>Mayor</hi> as the <hi>King</hi> thereof, and our <hi>Aldermen,</hi> as the Peers, the <hi>Commonalty</hi> the <hi>Commons</hi> thereof: We had power to make <hi>By-Laws</hi> and <hi>Ordinances</hi> in our <hi>Respective Companies;</hi> but now, alas! we are at present divested; but in expectation of the Princely Favour and Grace towards us, and that our Benign Prince will condescend to
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:101056:2"/>shew us Favour, and that we may build lastingly, we design to lay our Foundation low, to stoop low, humbly and submissively to our Prince, whose Favour, we do not despond of, through our humility, neither will we grow too much discontented with our loss, since our Grief in this case cannot avail us, but render us the more unhappy; for discontented men are as a Watch over-wound, wrested out of Tune, and going false; or like Ink poured into water, that fills the whole Fountain full of Blackness and Disuse, it casts the Soul into the shade, and fills it more with consideration of the unhappiness, than thought of the Remedy; nay it is so busied in contemplation of its Misery, as there is neither room nor time for seeking and requesting the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thods of <hi>Relief;</hi> but we will not so greatly lament as those without hope, which is as the miserable Mans God, that in the hardest gripe of Calamity, never fails to yield some Beams of comfort; therefore will we lie at the foot of our Gracious <hi>King,</hi> that he would let us rise as the <hi>Phoenix;</hi> and though we cannot forbear to mourn in some measure for our faults and for our loss, which if we could not la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, were hardness, but to mourn as desponding, is endless; for though we fall, yet our Confidence is, that we shall rise again, and that upon our humble submission, our <hi>Princes</hi> inclinations are so gracious, that we shall not abide <hi>Desolate,</hi> but be a <hi>Magnificent,</hi> a <hi>Loyal</hi> and <hi>Dutiful Corporation;</hi> which <hi>Submission, Loyalty</hi> and <hi>Obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience</hi> will render us desirable to our <hi>Prince,</hi> and give us a true and permanent Interest in his Favour and Benignity.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>A. Banks.</hi> MDCLXXXXIII.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>